

Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com www.LondonResearchInternational.com

Ms. Siziba

NATIONALITY: South Africa

SUMMARY

Vimbainashe Elizabeth Siziba graduated from the University of Cape Town, South Africa with an Honours degree in Environmental Management in 2009 and obtained a Bachelor of Social Science degree majoring in Environmental and Geographical Science and Sociology in December 2006. Since childhood, Vimbainashe has always been fascinated by the world of nature, hence her choice of degree programme. Through her study programme, she acquired a keen understanding of environmental issues and the related sociological complexities as well as strong critical thinking and analytical skills. She was privileged to interact with people from different social and racial backgrounds by virtue of schools and college attended as well as organisations worked for, consequently reinforcing in her strong inter-personal, communication skills and a profound sense of team spirit.

EDUCATION

- University of Cape Town 2009 Honours Environmental Management (Postgraduate)
 Environmental Management (EIA, EMS, Biodiversity), Research in Environmental Management,
 Disaster Risk Management, Living with Environmental Change (Climate Change issues)
- University of Cape Town 2004-2006 BSoc.Sci EGS and Sociology (Undergraduate)
 Introduction to Earth and Environmental Science, Human Geography, Earth Stewardship,
 Environmental Problems, Cities of the South, Italian Intensive 1 & 2, Poverty, Development and
 Globalization, Environmental Change, Urban Geography, Social Research, Democracy, Social
 Change and Development, Word Power.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Awarded the Dante Alighieri Book Prize for Italian Intensive at UCT – 25 May 2005

- Dominican Convent School 2002-2003 3 Advanced Levels
- Girls' High School 1998-2001 9 Ordinary Levels



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

www.LondonResearchInternational.com

EMPLOYMENT RECORD/PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NCC Environmental Services (subcontracted for Eskom)

(Mercury-Mookodi 400kV Powerline Project)

February 2012 to date

Environmental Officer, monitoring contractors' EMP compliance

Sasol Petroleum Temane (Mozambique)

April 2010-June 2011

Environmental Site Officer, (CPF183 Natural Gas Expansion Project-Construction) Project EMP compliance monitoring, auditing of contractors, spillage contamination investigation and remediation, monitoring erosion, dust, effluent, sewage, storm water hazardous materials, closure and rehabilitation planning, waste minimisation and separation at source, ensuring proper and safe disposal and recycling.

Peninsula Permits & Eco Services (Cape Town)

February 2008-April 2010

Environmental Control Officer on movies, commercials, stills shoots and events in conserved areas. Ensuring production company crews complied with filming permit conditions regarding rehabilitation & nature conservation of these areas.

• South Africa Education and Environment (Cape Town)

August to November 2009

Environmental Club

Project (SAEP) Volunteer Internship Educator at Zisukhanyo & Sophumelela High Schools

Environmental Management Agency (Harare, Zimbabwe)

January to December 2007

Provincial Environmental Education and Publicity Officer. Researched on and raised environmental awareness on pertinent environmental issues affecting the province. Liaised with the press on these and raised awareness to stakeholders such as schools, the police and farmers through campaigns on anti-littering, anti-illegal wood abstraction, anti-illegal sand abstraction, anti-illegal gold mining and fire awareness and fire fighting



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com
www.LondonResearchInternational.com

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS
n/a
PUBLICATIONS
n/a
LANGUAGES

English